[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "Q1) Which mechanical system resembles the human heart?",
        "options": [
            "Flywheel",
            "Hydraulic pump",
            "Governor",
            "Carburetor"
        ],
        "answer": "Hydraulic pump"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Q2) Why does a moving bicycle stay upright more easily?",
        "options": [
            "Air drag",
            "Tyre pressure",
            "Gyroscopic effect",
            "Rider's mass"
        ],
        "answer": "Gyroscopic effect"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Q3) What happens if you fill diesel in a petrol car?",
        "options": [
            "It runs smoother",
            "No effect",
            "Improves mileage",
            "Engine misfires and stalls"
        ],
        "answer": "Engine misfires and stalls"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Q4) Why are front bakes disc-type in most cars?",
        "options": [
            "For style",
            "Front handles more braking load",
            "Drum brakes heat faster",
            "To reduce cost"
        ],
        "answer": "Front handles more braking load"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Q5) What causes knocking in petrol engines?",
        "options": [
            "Premature ignition of fuel-air mix",
            "Wrong fuel filter",
            "Lack of lubrication",
            "Late ignition"
        ],
        "answer": "Premature ignition of fuel-air mix"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Q6) Why is aluminium used for some engine blocks?",
        "options": [
            "It's lighter and conducts heat better",
            "It's cheaper",
            "It's stronger",
            "It looks cooler"
        ],
        "answer": "It's lighter and conducts heat better"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Q7) Increasing compression ratio in an engine usually?",
        "options": [
            "Increases emissions only",
            "Increases efficiency",
            "Decreases efficiency",
            "No effect"
        ],
        "answer": "Increases efficiency"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Q8) What does a differential help with?",
        "options": [
            "Equal wheel speeds",
            "Fuel Economy",
            "Different wheel speeds during turns",
            "Steering stability"
        ],
        "answer": "Different wheel speeds during turns"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Q9) Why do cars have a radiator?",
        "options": [
            "Cool the engine",
            "Heat the cabin",
            "Filter fuel",
            "Increase exhaust pressure"
        ],
        "answer": "Cool the engine"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Q10) What does a flywheel do in an engine?",
        "options": [
            "Store heat",
            "Increase torques",
            "Reduce friction",
            "Store mechanicla energy to maintain speed"
        ],
        "answer": "Store mechanicla energy to maintain speed"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "Q11) Which law explains why passengers lurch forward when a car stops suddenly??",
        "options": [
            "Newton's 3rd law",
            "Newton's 1st law",
            "Newton's 2nd law",
            "Hooke's law"
        ],
        "answer": "Newton's 1st law"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "Q12) What does RPM stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Revolutions Per Minute",
            "Rotations Per Minute",
            "Revolutions Per Meter",
            "Rotation Power Mode"
        ],
        "answer": "Rotations Per Minute"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Q13) Which part of the engine stors energt to maintain smooth rotation?",
        "options": [
            "Piston",
            "Crankshaft",
            "Flywheel",
            "Camshaft"
        ],
        "answer": "Flywheel"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "Q14) Gear ratio is defined as?",
        "options": [
            "Speed of engine / Speed of wheels",
            "Torque / RPM",
            "Engine Power / Torque",
            "Number of gears / Wheel diameter"
        ],
        "answer": "Speed of engine / Speed of wheels"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "Q15) What does BHP stand for?",
        "options": [
            "Brake Horse Power",
            "Base Hydraulic Pressure",
            "Basic Heat Power",
            "Brake Heat Potential"
        ],
        "answer": "Brake Horse Power"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Q16) The main function of a carburetor is?",
        "options": [
            "Increase RPM",
            "Cool engine",
            "Filter exhaust gases",
            "Mix air and fuel"
        ],
        "answer": "Mix air and fuel"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Q17) Which lubricant is most commonly used in internal combustion engines?",
        "options": [
            "Oil",
            "Grease",
            "Diesel",
            "Engine Oil"
        ],
        "answer": "Engine Oil"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "Q18) In gear trains, the driver gear is?",
        "options": [
            "The gear that receives motion",
            "Always smaller",
            "Always larger",
            "The gear that transmits motion"
        ],
        "answer": "The gear that transmits motion"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "Q19) The process of reducing a solid metal's thickness by passing it through rollers is called?",
        "options": [
            "Casting",
            "Rolling",
            "Extrusion",
            "Forging"
        ],
        "answer": "Rolling"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "Q20) Why is stainless steel preferred for exhaust systems?",
        "options": [
            "Lightweight",
            "Conducts heat faster",
            "Corrosion resistance",
            "Cheaper than mild steel"
        ],
        "answer": "Corrosion resistance"
    }
]